# **Robert Krauss**

Halethorpe, MD 21227 rkj4108@gmail.com +1 443 956 9026

## **Professional Summary**

Hello, my name is Robert krauss I have been involved in the plumbing trade coming up on 9 years. I have most experience in new construction doing jobs anywhere from the ground up to rough and trim out along with doing work in existing buildings. I have experience with water, sewer, gas of most types of pipping and materials. I have experience in service work as well. I have completed jobs for gas stations, restaurants, stores, office buildings, airports, military bases, police precincts, city and county schools and maintenance yards. I am familiar with all basic hand and power tools as well as other larger power tools hammer drills, threading machines, snakes, tampers, core machines etc. I have limited knowledge with skid steers and small excavators.

Authorized to work in the US for any employer

### Work Experience

#### Plumber

Langenfelder mechanical-Dundalk, MD September 2023 to March 2024

I currently hold a tech position running service calls from various state buildings city and county schools state Highway buildings etc. most of the repairs are swapping out failed devices replacing fixtures replacing burst broken or leaking pipe work and utilizing various snakes for clogged drains. The construction side deals with roof drain replacements when schools tear off for a new roof so there is roof drain and underneath pipe replacement.

#### **Plumber**

BMC Services-Baltimore, MD October 2020 to November 2022

Plumber. Handeling small jobs of my own and working as a team on large projects

#### **Plumber**

Plumbing

Lawver plumbing-Baltimore, MD January 2013 to January 2018

Plumbers apprentice. Plumber. Handeling small to large projects and working as a team on various other small and large projects.

Education			
None			
Skills			

- · Pipe Threading
- Forklift
- Construction
- · Materials Handling
- Blueprint Reading
- Mowing
- Groundskeeping
- · Tree trimming
- Driving

# Certifications and Licenses

#### **OSHA 10**

### Plumbing apprenticeship

### Assessments

# **Construction safety — Proficient**

August 2023

Using safe practices while on a construction site

Full results: Proficient

## **Work style: Reliability — Proficient**

July 2023

Tendency to be reliable, dependable, and act with integrity at work

Full results: Proficient

### **Mechanical knowledge — Proficient**

July 2023

Understanding and applying mechanical concepts and processes

Full results: Proficient

#### **Basic maintenance and repair — Proficient**

September 2023

Performing basic repairs and maintenance for apartment complexes, office buildings, and other

facilities

Full results: Proficient

Indeed Assessments provides skills tests that are not indicative of a license or certification, or continued development in any professional field.